Finding Aid for Arthur J. Lacy Papers, 1891-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur J. Lacy Papers
1891-1975
Lacy, Arthur J. (Arthur Jay), 1876-1975.
Detroit, Michigan, attorney and judge, Democratic candidate for governor in 1934. Correspondence, legal case files, family materials, speeches, essays, diary notes, financial materials, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, photographs, and transcript of oral interview.
85824 Aa 2 AC Ac
10 linear feet
2 oversize folders
1 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The major portion of the collection was donated by the estate of Arthur J. Lacy (donor no. 2601 ) in 1975. Other earlier materials were donated by Mr. Lacy in several different accession beginning in 1975.
The collection is open for research.
Arthur J. Lacy was born September 30,1876 in Nirvana, a lumbering town in Lake County, Michigan. His family was large and exceptionally close and from an early age, as the oldest living child, he participated in the family businesses. He attended school until he was twelve, but received most of his literary education at home. As a teenager he passed Michigan's school teachers' examination and taught in a one room school for a year. In 1894, he went to seek a law degree at Northern Indiana Normal School at Valparaiso, Indiana (now Valparaiso University), and in two years was admitted to the Indiana bar although he was underage. In 1896, he began the study of law at the University of Michigan which he completed in 1898. In 1899, he and his wife Beth Garwick Lacy settled in Clare, Michigan, where he set up his law practice.
In 1902, he was elected to his first of four terms as mayor. Retiring from that office in 1906, he later sought the office of prosecuting attorney, for which he was defeated. In 1909, he accepted an invitation from Alfred Lucking, Henry Ford's lawyer, to practice law in Detroit. Governor Woodbridge Ferris, with whom he had corresponded since childhood, appointed Lacy judge of the new Detroit Domestic Relations Court in 1913. Lacy under-took initial organization of the court, which had jurisdiction over divorce and family cases. The court was dissolved eight months later in 1914, by the Michigan Supreme Court and Lacy again entered private practice in the law firm of Anderson, Rackham, and Wilcox, replacing the retiring Horace Rackham.
In 1920, he was appointed head of the Detroit Civil Service Commission by Mayor James Couzens, whose private attorney he was until Couzen's death. In 1923-1928, he represented Couzens in the Ford Stock Tax Case, and was instrumental in the settlement of the case in favor of the stockholders. Lacy also wrote for Couzens the instrument of Trust setting up the Children's Fund of Michigan. In 1930, Lacy began a personal campaign to reduce heavy taxes during the depression, which he thought could be done by decreasing the cost of government. In 1932 and 1933, he assisted thirty small Michigan banks in avoiding panic and remaining solvent. He was also deeply involved in the Detroit bank crisis of 1933 and co-author of the Michigan Emergency Banking Act. These public involvements catapulted him into prominence in the Democratic party.
In 1934, Lacy was mentioned as a candidate for U.S. Senator. But only after great persuasion did he enter the Democratic gubernatorial primary to challenge successfully the current governor William A. Comstock. In the November election, he ran against Republican Frank Fitzgerald, but was defeated. Lacy's political decline was apparently rapid. He devoted his time to his legal practice and philanthropic activities that included the Salvation Army, the Boys' Club of Detroit, and the Youth Services of the Knights Templar, Grand Commandery of Detroit. He also began to diverge politically from Franklin D. Roosevelt, recoiling from deficit spending, the welfare state, attempted court packing, and Roosevelt's intention to run for a third term. Lacy, however, was never welcomed as a statesman in the Republican party.
In 1947, Lacy retired from active participation in his law firm and cut back his legal work. He remained involved in income tax cases, a field in which he was considered an expert. Most of his public activities were connected with philanthropy, although he served on the National Sanitation Foundation and on the Board of Directors of the Parker Rust Proof Company. He died in 1975.
The Arthur J. Lacy collection consists of correspondence and other papers documenting his political activities within the Democratic party and career as a Detroit attorney. The collection has been divided into the following series: Biographical information; Personal letters; Professional correspondence and related papers; Lacy Family papers; Speeches; Early personal materials; Writings, essays, etc.; Financial files; Miscellaneous; Newspapers clippings; Photographs; and Legal files.
The Lacy Collection documents particularly well Lacy's major legal cases (Wilson vs. White, the Ford Stock Tax Case, Mary A. Rackham Estate) and his transition from conservative Democrat to conservative Republican. His letters home from Valparaiso, Indiana and Ann Arbor and his letters to his future wife Beth Garwick give a detailed picture of college life in the 1890's. Major subjects covered in the public papers are the Detroit Domestic Relations Court, problems of taxation and banking in the depression, Lacy's friendship with James Couzens, and the campaigns of 1932 and 1934. A series of notes Lacy wrote to himself from 1915-1928 and 1946-1956 reveal his political ideals, personal morality, and his relationship to his family.
Within the Professional Correspondence and related papers series, the researcher will find correspondence with many notable political and business figures. These include John W. Anderson, William R. Angell, Art Baker, Arthur A. Ballantine, C.C. Bradner, John V. Brennan, Thomas E. Brennan, Prentiss M. Brown, Wilber M. Brucker, George E. Bushnell, Daniel T. Campau, Harvey J. Campbell, John J. Carson, E.R. Chapin, John S. Coleman, William A. Comstock, Calvin Coolidge, Grace G. Coolidge, Frank Couzens, James J. Couzens, John D. Dingell, Patrick J. Doyle, William J. Durant, Henry T. Ewald, Mordecai J.B. Ezechiel, James A. Farley, Homer Ferguson, Woodbridge N. Ferris, Clara J.B. Ford, Edsel B. Ford, Joseph Foss, Fred W. Green, Alexander J. Groesbeck, Edgar A. Guest, James M. Hare, Herbert C. Hoover, J. Edgar Hoover, Kaufman T. Keller, Stanley S. Kresge, David Lawrence, Arthur F. Lederle, John C. Lehr, Fulton Lewis, Percy Loud, William G. McAdoo, William McKinley, George A. Marston, Eliza M. Mosher, Frank Murphy, George Murphy, William J. Norton, George D. O'Brien, Elmer B. O'Hara, Hazen S. Pingree, Mary A. H. Rackham, Horace H. Rackham, Clarence A. Reid, George W. Romney, Eleanor Roosevelt, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Alexander G. Ruthven, W.M. Skillman, Albert E. Sleeper, Edward D. Stair, Arthur E. Summerfield, William H. Taft, Joseph P. Tumulty, Arthur H. Vandenberg, A. VanderZee, Murray D. Van Wagoner, Henry F. Vaughan, Carl Vinson, Matilda R.D. Wilson, Clarence E. Wilcox, and R.A.C. Wollenberg.
The Lacy Family papers are rich in detail about life in Michigan in the nineteenth and early twentieth century; the surviving letters document family crises and Lacy's role in them as the oldest and most successful child and later, as family leader. Lacy was the family genealogist and he collected and preserved the family correspondence of his uncles and aunt, some of which date back to the 1850's.
Subjects:
Arbitration, International.; Banks and banking--Michigan.; Boys Club of Detroit (Mich.); Children's Fund of Michigan.; Civil rights--Michigan.; Civil service.; Clare (Mich.); Cold war.; Constitutional law--United States.; Crime.; Debts, Public--United States.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Depressions--1929--Michigan.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit Bar Association.; Detroit (Mich.). Mayor's Committee on Youth Problems.; Detroit (Mich.). Milk Arbitration Board.; Detroit Trust Company.; Elections--Michigan--1932.; Elections--Michigan--1934.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Ford Motor Company.; Hawaii.; Hiss, Alger.; Immigrants--Michigan.; Jewish-Arab relations.; Judges--Michigan--Detroit.; Juvenile delinquency--Michigan.; Knights Templar (Masonic order); Labor unions--Michigan.; Lacy, Arthur J. (Arthur Jay), 1876-1975.; Lawyers--Michigan--Detroit.; League of Nations.; Mexico--Frontier troubles--1910-; Michigan. Commission on Codification of Laws.; Michigan. Court of Domestic Relations (Wayne County); Michigan--Emigration and immigration.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1917-1921.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Municipal government--Michigan.; Nirvana (Mich.); Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Northern Indiana Normal School and Business Institute (Valparaiso, Ind.); Oral history.; Philippines--History--1898-1946.; Plunkett, Horace Curzon, Sir, 1854-1932.; Prohibition--Michigan.; Salvation Army.; Sit-down strikes--Michigan.; Taxation--Michigan.; Temperance--Michigan.; Trusts, Industrial.; United States. Army--History--Punitive Expedition into Mexico, 1916.Punitive Expedition into Mexico, 1916.History; United States. Labor Management Relations Act, 1947.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law. Class of 1898.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1891-1900.StudentsSocial life and customs1891-1900.; Wayne County (Mich.); Women--Suffrage--United States.; Women's rights--United States.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Finance--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Detroit (Mich.). Civil Service Commission.; Detroit Federation of Woman's Clubs.; Detroit (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Dwellings--Michigan--Detroit.; Dwellings--Michigan--Nirvana.; Foxville (Mich.); Golf.; Lacy family.; Lumber industry.; Nirvana (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Schools--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law. Class of 1898.; Women.
Contributors:
Anderson, John Wendell, 1867-1945.; Angell, William Robert, 1877-1950.; Baker, Art.; Ballantine, Arthur A. (Arthur Atwood), b. 1883.; Bradner, C. C.; Brennan, John V., 1872-1971.; Brennan, Thomas E.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Bushnell, George E. (George Edward), 1887-1965.; Campau, Daniel J., 1852-1897.; Campbell, Harvey J., 1890-; Carson, John Joseph, 1889-; Chapin, E. R.; Coleman, John Strider, 1897-1958.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Coolidge, Grace Goodhue, 1879-1957.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Dingell, John D. (John David), 1894-1955.; Doyle, Patrick J.; Durant, Will, 1885-1981.; Ewald, Henry Theodore, 1885-1953.; Ezechiel, Mordecai Joseph Brill, 1899-; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.; Ferris, Woodbridge N., 1853-1928.; Ford, Clara Bryant, 1866-1950.; Ford, Edsel, 1893-1943.; Foss, Joe, 1915-2003; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Guest, Edgar A. (Edgar Albert), 1881-1959.; Hare, James M. (James McNeil), 1910-1980; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Keller, Kaufman Thuma, 1885-1966.; Kresge, Stanley Sebastian, 1900-; Lawrence, David, 1888-; Lederle, Arthur F., 1887-; Lehr, John Camillus, 1878-1958.; Lewis, Fulton, 1903-1966.; Loud, Percy.; McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1863-1941.; McKinley, William, 1843-1901.; Marston, George A.; Mosher, Eliza Maria, 1846-1928.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murphy, George, 1897-1961.; Norton, William J. (William John), 1883-1975.; O'Brien, George Donoghue, 1900-1957.; O'Hara, Elmer B.; Pingree, Hazen S., 1840-1901.; Rackham, Mary A. Horton, d. 1947.; Rackham, Horace H., 1858-1933.; Reid, Clarence A.; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Skillman, W. McKay, 1894-; Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.; Stair, Edward Douglas, b. 1859.; Summerfield, Arthur Ellsworth, 1899-1972.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Tumulty, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1879-1954.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Vander Zee, A.; Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-; Vaughan, Henry F. (Henry Frieze), 1889-1979; Vinson, Carl, 1883-1981.; Wilson, Matilda R. Dodge.; Wilcox, Clarence Edward, 1880-1958.; Wollenberg, R. A. C.
Genre/Form:
Cartoons.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Tintypes.
- Biographical information
  - Transcript of oral interviews with AJL conducted by Richard T. Ortquist and Marvin Petroelje (Box 1, Folder 1a)
  - Personal sketch published in The Lawyer and Banker and Southern Bench and Bar Review, August 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1b)
  - Miscellaneous biographical (Box 1, Folder 1c)
- Personal Letters
  - Card index to correspondence (Box 1)
  - Letters written from Northern Indiana Normal School, undated; September 1894-May 1896; 15 folders (Box 1, Folder 2-16)
  - Letters written from the University of Michigan, December 1896-May 1898; 4 folders (Box 1, Folder 17-20)
  - Courtship letters between Arthur Lacy and Beth Garwick, August 1896-December 1898; 13 folders (Box 1, Folder 21-33)
    (include reminiscences of Lacy's marriage proposal to Beth Garwick, November 1897 in folder 28)
- Professional Correspondence and related papers
  - 1895-1914, 14 folders (Box 1, Folder 34-47)
  - Report of the Wayne County Domestic Relations Court, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - 1915-1919, 5 folders (Box 1, Folder 49-53)
  - 1920-1924, 5 folders (Box 2, Folder 54-58)
  - Alabama Timber Case correspondence, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - 1925-May 1934, 41 folders (Box 2, Folder 60-100)
  - Letters urging Lacy to run for Senator or Governor, undated; April 1934 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Letters urging Lacy to run for Governor, May-September 1934; 6 folders (Box 2, Folder 102-107)
  - Letters written by Edwin Goodwin for William J. Williams on behalf of Lacy, July-September 1934 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - July 1934-December 1940, 12 folders (Box 2, Folder 109-120)
  - 1941-1947, 11 folders (Box 3, Folder 121-131)
  - Mary A. Rackham estate income tax liability case, November 1948-1951; 5 folders (Box 3, Folder 132-136)
  - 1948-1974, 28 folders (Box 3, Folder 137-164)
- Lacy Family Papers
  - Undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Essay and autobiography by Florence May Lacy, 1884-1907 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - 1876-1905, 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 167-168)
  - Letters of Arthur Lacy to Beth Lacy, November-December 1901; September 1904; 3 folders (Box 3, Folder 168-171)
  - April 1906-December 1906, 4 folders (Box 4, Folder 172-175)
  - Letters from Francis D. Lacy to his family while he was confined in insane asylums, 1906 undated (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - 1907-1973, 33 folders (Box 4, Folder 177-209)
  - Eunice Amelia Stevens Lacy (1858-1924) notebook, marriage certificate and poem of, undated (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Francis D. Lacy (1838-1907) poems and essays (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - Thomas J. Lacy (1828-1917) correspondence and other papers (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Lucy M. Lacy Kilparick (1845-1885) correspondence (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1858-1885 (Box 4, Folder 214a)
  - Beth Garwick Lacy
    - Essays, 1903-1904 (Box 4, Folder 214b)
    - Two early notebooks (Box 4, Folder 214c)
    - Minutes of the Salvation Army Auxiliary, 1927-1939 (Box 4, Folder 214d)
- Speeches
  - Undated (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Speech extracts, 1895-1897 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - 1901-1956 (scattered dates), 10 folders (Box 5, Folder 217-226)
- Early Personal Materials
  - Childhood miscellanea (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Teaching certificates grade reports, 1891-1892 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Book lists, account books, notebooks from rhetoric class, letters of recommendation from Northern Indiana Normal School (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Debating notes, from Northern Indiana Normal School (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Composition book 1895-1896 essays, 1894-1896 from Northern Indiana Normal School (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Composition book containing essays, epigrams, poetry, debating notes, circa 1895-1898 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Essay, speeches delivered in debate, Club memberships from the University of Michigan Law School (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Class notes 1897-1898 study guide, 1898 from the University of Michigan Law School (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Notebooks kept for self improvement, 1897-1898 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - Notebooks kept for self improvement, 1904; undated (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Notebooks kept for self improvement, 1904; undated (Box 5, Folder 236a)
- Writings, essays, etc
  - Writings, unclassified, undated; 1915 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1910-1912; undated (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - Essays, undated; 1895-1957 (scattered dates); 7 folders (Box 5, Folder 239-245)
  - Poems, 1893-1968; undated (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Sketches (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Newspaper clippings Northwestern Detroit Review articles by "Axy Dent" (Arthur J. Lacy), 1911-1912 (Box 5, Folder 248a)
  - Scrapbook containing extracts from letters, essays, speeches, poems, and editorials, 1896-1908 (Box 5)
    (table of contents in front of volume)
  - Notebook, April 10, 1910-March 3, 1912 (Box 6)
  - Notebook, March 12, 1912-February 21, 1915 (Box 6)
  - Notebook, March 4, 1915-October 21, 1920 (Box 6)
  - Notebook, September 30, 1923-February 3, 1924 (Box 6)
    (includes genealogical tables)
  - Notebook, October 28, 1928-April 7, 1929; January 8, 1932; January 8, 1933; August 23, 1944; September 4, 1944; October 5, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Notes, 1927-1930; undated (Box 6, Folder 248b)
  - Notes, 1942-1950; 12 folders (Box 6, Folder 249-260)
  - Notes, 1951-1958; 12 folders (Box 7, Folder 261-272)
- Financial Files
  - Personal Financial Inventories, 1929; 1930; 1936; 1941; 1944; 1961 (Box 7, Folder 273)
  - Papers relating to Lacy's house, 1923-1928 (Box 7, Folder 274)
  - Personal Financial Records, 1924-1926
    - 1924-1926 (Box 7)
    - 1931-January, 1936 (Box 7)
    - 1936-January, 1947 (Box 7)
    - January 1947-June 10, 1968 (Box 7)
    - 1956-1966 (Box 7)
  - Record of Gifts, 1935-1966 (Box 7)
  - Investments in Pacific Gas & Electric Co., 1945-1961 (Box 7, Folder 276)
- Miscellaneous
  - Journal of trip to Europe, 1928 (Box 8)
  - Miscellanea, University of Michigan Alumni Association (Box 8)
  - Certificates and awards; confidential report of the Boys' Club of Detroit, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 289)
  - University of Michigan Law School, class of biographical information, 1898; 6 folders (Box 8)
- Newspaper clippings
  - Undated, 1892-1930; 12 folders (Box 8, Folder 295-307)
  - 1931-1970, 6 folders (Box 9, Folder 308-313)
  - Detroit Domestic Relations Court scrapbooks, 1913-1914; 2 volumes (Box 9)
  - National Association of Real Estate Boards, Property Owners Division scrapbooks, January 1931-January 1932; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    (AJL was chairman)
  - Scrapbook containing editorial comments on politics, banking and taxation (Volume 1)
    (located in AC)
- Photographs
  - De Lacy family, Alicante, Spain 's, 1930 (Box 9)
  - Early photos, A. J. Lacy (Box 9)
    (includes photos of school at Foxville, Mich.)
  - Early photos, family (Box 9)
  - Early photos, miscellaneous (Box 9)
    (includes photo of the Lacy sawmill at Nirvana, ca. 1908)
    (also in Uax images)
  - Eunice Amelia Stevens Lacy (Box 9)
  - Frank H. Lacy (Box 9)
  - Golfing associates, club (Box 9)
  - Homes: includes photos of Lacy home at Nirvan (Box 9)
  - Howrani family (Box 9)
  - Law School (Box 9)
  - Personal, family, friends, 1920s-1960s (Box 9)
    (includes photo of Executive Board, Detroit Federation of Women's Clubs, 1920s)
  - Portraits (Box 9)
    (also oversize portraits)
  - Portraits: cartoon (Box 9)
  - Public appearances, groups, meetings, 1920s-1960s (Box 9)
    (includes photos of Detroit Civil Service Commission, 1920)
- Legal Files
  - Wilson vs. White (Box 10)
    - Brief for Plaintiffs & Appellees (1923) (Box 10)
    - Reply Brief of Appellees (1923) (Box 10)
    - Decree of Supreme Court, State of Michigan (Box 10)
  - Ford Stock Tax Case
    - Brief to the Honorable Commissioner of Internal Revenue (Box 10)
    - Brief in behalf of James Couzens (Box 10)
    - Reply brief for Petitioners John F. Dodge and Horace E. Dodge estates (Box 10)
    - Appeal of Rosetta V. Hauss (Box 10)
    - Appeal of James Couzens (December 29, 1925) (Box 10)
    - Appeal of Horace Rackham (January 11, 1926) (Box 10)
    - Petitioners' brief and argument (April 18, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Petitioners' Statement of Facts (April 18, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Brief of Respondent (April 18, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Reply Brief on Behalf of Rosetta V. Hauss (May 12, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Reply to Respondent's Brief on collateral issues (May 12, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Reply Brief for Petitioner, Horace H. Rackham (May 13, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Petitioners' Reply Brief on Behalf of Paul R. Gray, David Gray and Estate of Philip H. Gray, deceased (May 16, 1927) (Box 10)
    - Memorandum of Argument on Behalf of the Dodges on the Question of the effect on certain "Waivers" on Statute of Limitations (Box 10)
    - Chronological record of Ford Stock Tax Case (1919-1925), legal brief and correspondence presented as evidence in the Ford Stock Tax Case, record of fees (Box 10)
    - Exhibits (incomplete) presented in Ford Stock Tax Case litigation (Box 10)
  - Estate of Mary A. Rackham
    - Record on Appeal (Box 10)
    - Brief for Department of Revenue, Defendant-Appellant and Crass-Appellants (Box 10)
    - Brief of Christian Science Benevolent Association, Christian Science Pleasant View Home, and Christian Science Benevolent Association on Pacific Coast (Box 10)
    - Brief for Detroit Trust Company, former Trustee, and the Administrators of the Estate of Mary A. Rackham, deceased, Respondents-Appellees and Crass-Appellants (Box 10)
    - Mary A. Rackham estate: accounts, petitions and other papers filed in Probate Court (Box 10)
  - Law Office miscellaneous
    - Financial Statements of Anderson, Wilcox, & Lacy and Anderson, Wilcox, Lacy & Lawson; Summaries 1917-1946 yearly records, 1914-1915, 1920-1924, 1927-1934 (Box 10)
    - Financial Statements of Anderson, Wilcox, Lacy & Lawson, yearly records, 1935-1942; 1944-1947 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence of Anderson & Rackham Law Firm, concerning Ford Motor Co., and other legal affairs, 1903-1905 (Box 10)
    - Legal opinions relating to income taxes on soap formula royalties, undated, and legal brief, 1907 (Box 10)
    - An analysis of the Detroit Trust Company, June 2, 1936 Memo on Lacy's purchases of Detroit Trust Co. stock, 1939 Stock purchases, 1942 (Box 10)
    - The Facts on the Couzens' donation creating the Children's Fund of Michigan (Box 10)
    - William A. Angell will; trust instrument creating the Angell Foundation; Angell Foundation minutes; handwritten record of estate matters (Box 10)
    - Anderson, Wilcox and Lacy, office manual, undated (Box 10)
Partial Subject Index to Correspondence
Banks and banking--Michigan Banking crisis in Michigan and Detroit in 1932-1933. [folder 79-98]
Boys Club of Detroit (Mich.) Confidential report on Boys' Club activities, 1942 [in box 8].
Children's Fund of Michigan Letter to Board of Trustees, June 7, 1934; letter from William Norton, Aug. 1, 1934; letter to Detroit Historical Society, May 15, 1956; and report on the Couzens' donations creating the Children's Fund [in box 10]
Civil Service Civil Service reform, especially essays, 192? and Dec. 4, 1920 [in folder 242] and correspondence throughout.
Clare (Mich.) Clare, Michigan in correspondence throughout.